we've been given
a local variable pets which references
an array of strings
and each one of these strings represents
a pet
the problem asks us to select the string
fish from pets and assign the return
value to a variable named my pet
we will then print the value of my pet
as part of the sentence
i have a pet fish
so this problem has a couple of steps
and we'll begin
by just selecting fish from pets
we can access a specific element from an
array
using its index in this array we can see
that
fish is the third element
in order to access an element of an
array by its index
we use the syntax seen on line three
and that syntax with the brackets is
actually an
array method this is an element
reference
and it will return the element at the
specified index
you can see that on line 3 we've placed
the index
three in those brackets
and we chose three because we can see
that there are
four elements in the pets array and fish
is the third element
let's run our code and see if we output
phish
and we do not we actually see the output
lizard
looking back at our code you can see
that lizard is the
last element in the pet's array
there are four total elements and lizard
is the fourth
so it may seem confusing that lizard is
returned
when we access the element at index 3.
that's because arrays have a 0 based
index
the first element of an array will be at
0 rather than index 1.
this also means that the last element of
the array
will have an index that is 1 less than
the total size of the array
so now let's access the element at index
0 of our pets array and this time we're
expecting to see the string cat
and we do
we now know that we would expect fish to
be at index
two so let's access the element of our
array at index
two and make sure that the output is
fish
now that we're accessing the correct
element of our pet's array
let's follow the next step of our
problem and
assign it to the variable my pet
now we want to print my pet as part of a
sentence
we want to output i have a pet fish
in order for our output to match the
example
output we could use either string
concatenation
or string interpolation
so let's use interpolation
and now check whether our output matches
the expected output
and it does
always remember when accessing elements
from an array
that array indexes begin at zero
you